Finding Aid for School of Natural Resources and Environment (University of Michigan) Records 1903-2012.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- School Reviews, 1967-1984
  - 1982-1984 Reviews, 1976-1982
    - Questions from the Review Committee
      - General (Note: it is helpful to view "general" prior to questions) (Box 11)
      - Questions #1-28-B, 29 folders (Box 11)
    - Reports (used as support documents for the 1982-1984 Reviews)
      - The Context of Interdisciplinary Team Research in SNR, 1980
      - Ecology, Fisheries and Wildlife Program Evaluation, 1980 (Box 11)
      - Ecology, Fisheries and Wildlife Program Review, 1980 (Box 11)
      - Ecology, Fisheries and Wildlife Program Site Visit, 1980 (Box 11)
      - Landscape Architecture Program ASLA Evaluation Report, 1976 (Box 11)
    - Reports (used as support documents for the 1982-1984 Reviews)
      - Report of the Committee on Environmental Resources, Planning and Design (Norman Report), 1975 (Box 12)
      - Resource Policy and Management Program Site Visit Report, 1980 (Box 12)
      - Resource Policy and Management Program Survey of Students and Alumni, 1979 (Box 12)
      - SNR Status and Direction for the Future, 1981 (Box 12)
      - Self Evaluation Report for USDA, CSRS Site Visit, 1985 (Box 12)
      - Self Evaluation Report of the Resource Policy and Management Program, 1980 (Box 12)
    - Review Topical Folders
      - Ascendancy Curve (Box 12)
      - "Bill's" Speech (Dean William J. Johnson) (Box 12)
      - Budget Priorities Report (Box 12)
      - Budgeting Project (Box 12)
      - Cash Flow Analysis (Box 12)
      - Charge Questions (Box 12)
      - Communications Committee Minutes (Box 12)
      - Data Collected and Sent to Review Committee, 1981-1982 (Box 12)
      - Development at SNR, 1962-1972 (Box 12)
      - Early Preparation Materials (Box 12)
      - Enrollment Levels and Retention Rates (Box 12)
      - Evaluation Plan-School, 1979-1980 (Box 12)
      - Evaluation Reports, 1970-1980 (Box 12)
      - Executive Officers
        - Decisions (Box 12)
        - Hearings (Box 12)
      - External Review
        - General (Box 12)
        - Advisory Visit, 2 folders (Box 12)
        - Feedback from Programs (Box 12)
        - Response (Box 12)
      - Faculty Update (Box 12)
      - Five Year Development/Strategy Plan (Box 12)
      - Follow-up Proposals for Info Sheet (Box 12)
      - Frye, Provost, Visit by (Box 12)
      - Full Time Employees (Box 12)
      - FYES Analysis, 1976-1981 (Box 12)
      - FYES Info LSA & SNR (Box 12)
      - Inaccuracies (Box 13)
      - Inputs (Box 13)
      - Johnson, Dean W.J., Notes (Box 13)
      - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 13)
      - Notes (Box 13)
      - Persistence Data (Box 13)
      - Productivity, Research (Box 13)
      - Resource Policy and Management Review, 1981 (Box 13)
      - Resource Policy and Management Self Evaluation, 1980 (Box 13)
      - Review Committee
        - Charge (Box 13)
        - Meetings, 3 folders (Box 13)
        - Report
          - Faculty Comments (Box 13)
          - Response
            - Administration (Box 13)
            - Students (Box 13)
      - Self Evaluation Drafts (Box 13)
      - Statistical Profiles, Full-time Employees (Box 13)
      - Total Enrollment and Credit Hours, 1980 (Box 13)
      - Transition Team, 3 folders (Box 13)
  - 1977 Special Review Report (Box 44)
  - 1982 Review, 1981-1982
    - Academic Programs
      - General (Box 44)
      - Analytics (Box 44)
      - Integrative Studies (Box 44)
    - Alumni Support (Box 44)
    - Budget (Box 44)
    - Communications Committee (Box 44)
    - Coordinating Committee (Box 44)
    - External Review Report, 1981 (Box 44)
    - Faculty Input and Meetings (Box 44)
    - Handwritten Notes (Box 44)
    - Letters of Support (Box 44)
    - News clippings (Box 44)
    - Provost Frye, Correspondence with (Box 44)
    - Public Hearings (Box 44)
    - Research Productivity (Box 44)
    - Review Committee (Box 44)
    - Review Process (materials about) (Box 44)
    - Statistics and Data (includes enrollment) (Box 44)
    - Strategy Plan (Box 44)
    - Students (Box 44)
    - Undergraduate Committee (Box 44)
  - 1983 Transition Team
    - 1983 Transition Team Topical Files, 1983-1984
      (includes records from 1984 re: implementation of Development Plan)
      - Academic Programs and Curricula (Box 44)
      - Administration/Governance/Organization (Box 44)
      - Alumni Visiting Committee (Box 44)
      - Budget and Funding (Box 44)
      - Camp Committee (Box 44)
      - CRAS Data (Box 44)
      - Dean's Correspondence (Box 44)
      - Design Criteria and Mission (Box 44)
      - Development Plan (Box 44)
      - Development Plan Task Forces
        - General, 1983 (Box 44)
        - Task Force #1: Research Task Force, 1983 (Box 44)
        - Task Force #2: Academic Affairs Task Force
          - Agenda, 1983 (Box 44)
          - Memoranda #1-38, 1983 (Box 44)
          - Miscellaneous Memoranda, 1983 (Box 44)
          - Minutes #1-30, 1983 (Box 44)
        - Task Force #3: Integrative Studies and Core Courses Task Force
          - Major Reports, 1983 (Box 44)
          - Memoranda and Minutes, 1983 (Box 44)
        - Task Force #4: Concentration and Specialization Courses Sub Task Force, 1983; 3 folders (Box 44)
        - Task Force #5: Academic Services Task Force
          - Major Report, 1983 (Box 44)
          - Memoranda and Minutes, 1983 (Box 44)
      - Environmental Advocacy (Box 46)
      - Evaluative Criteria (Box 46)
      - Executive Committee (Box 46)
      - External Advisory Group (Box 46)
      - Faculty
        - General (Box 46)
        - Faculty Expertise
          - General, 2 folders (Box 46)
          - Configurations at a 33% Reduction Level (Box 46)
        - Faculty "Fit"
          - General (Box 46)
          - Faculty Evaluations and Reduction (Box 53)
        - Joint Appointments (Box 46)
        - Meetings and Workshops (Box 46)
        - Performance Standards (Box 46)
        - Teaching Loads (Box 46)
      - Integrative/Interdisciplinary Studies (Box 46)
      - Masters Programs
        - Alternative Designs (Box 46)
        - Faculty Responses, 2 folders (Box 46)
      - Memorandum of Understanding (Box 46)
      - Peer Schools (Box 46)
      - Planning Process and Implementation (Box 46)
      - Press Releases (Box 46)
      - Report, 2 folders (Box 46)
      - Research Plan (Box 46)
      - Space and Facilities (Box 46)
      - Students and Student Committee (Box 47)
      - Task Forces
        - General (Box 47)
        - Analytics Task Force (Box 47)
        - Midcareer Program (Box 47)
        - Ph.D. Program (Box 47)
        - Staff Advisory Task Force (Box 47)
        - Undergraduate Program (Box 47)
      - Teaching Assistants (Box 47)
      - Transition Team Meetings, 9 folders (Box 47)
      - Vice President for Academic Affairs, Memos to and Meetings with (Box 47)
    - 1983 Transition Team Numbered Documents
      - #1-40 (Box 47)
      - #41-70 (Box 47)
      - #91-120 (Box 47)
      - #121-150 (Box 47)
      - #151-160 (Box 47)
      - #161-175 (Box 47)
      - #176-209 (Box 47)
- Student Papers, 1963-1973
  The Student Papers series (1 linear ft.) is arranged alphabetically by author. The papers were written for Dr. William J. Johnson's Landscape Architecture classes from 1963 to 1973, and topics relate to Michigan communities and water bodies, and the University of Michigan.
  - Burge, W. G. "A Visual Impression of the Ingalls Street Mall,", 1963 (Box 14)
    (re: University of Michigan)
  - Cefalo, Stephen R. "Site Concept," (re: Arbor Oaks Subdivision-Ann Arbor, Michigan), undated (Box 14)
  - Cefalo, Stephen. "Study Framework for Mackinac Island,", 1971 (Box 14)
  - Christoph, Ann & et al. "Manchester: A Study of its Visual Character,", 1971 (Box 14)
  - Crasco, Ken & et al. "CSC North Campus: A Study of Program Development,", 1965 (Box 14)
  - Dansard, Jo. "Study Framework for Mackinac Island Development Mackinac Island State Commission,", undated (Box 14)
  - Dik, Margery P. "Dixiboro Heights: A Neighborhood Unit,", 1972 (Box 14)
  - Dimond, Connie, editor. "An Exploratory Design Approach to Selected Regional Planning Issues,", undated (Box 14)
    (re: Grand Traverse Bay)
  - Duvall, Andrew & et al. "Manchester, Michigan,", undated (Box 14)
  - Edgerton, Ronald K. "The Preservation of Our Heritage,", 1971 (Box 14)
    (re: Ann Arbor)
  - Eldridge, Barron. "Arbor Mt. Housing Study,", 1972 (Box 14)
  - Eldridge, Barron. "Arbor Oaks Neighborhood Center,", 1971 (Box 14)
  - Ensign, Donald H. & et al. "Exploration of Community in Transition,", 1967 (Box 14)
  - Frankel, Betty. "Planning Policy in Farmington Township,", 1968 (Box 14)
  - Happel, Larry W. "Mackinac Island Study Proposal,", 1971 (Box 14)
  - Jarvis, Fred & et al. "A Future Plan for the Preservation of the Past,", 1967 (Box 14)
    (re: Ella Sharp Museum, Jackson, Michigan)
  - Johnson, William. "Grand Traverse County Development Guidelines,", 1973; 2 folders (Box 14)
    (9 student papers written and bound together for Professor Johnson)
  - Kreisman, Jane & et al. "Coastal Wetlands with emphasis on Freshwater Systems,", 1976; 2 folders (Box 14)
  - Lynn, Yolande Y. Y. "Mackinac Island,", undated (Box 14)
  - McCauley, John. "A Study Framework for the Development of Mackinac Island,", 1971 (Box 14)
  - Melstrom, James F. "A Neighborhood Center for Northwest Ann Arbor,", 1971 (Box 14)
  - Morabito, D. "Boardman River Watershed Study,", 1972 (Box 14)
  - Mustonen, Erik. "Management of the Boardman As a Natural River: Some Preliminary Recommendations for Discussion,", 1972 (Box 14)
  - Mustonen, Erik. "The Neighborhood Center: A Conceptualization,", undated (Box 14)
  - Phillips, David. "Synopsis-Recreation Study for the Whitmore Lake Area,", 1973 (Box 14)
  - Sabold, Wood. "Plan Study Approach for Mackinac Island,", 1971 (Box 14)
  - Stout, ? "Guide, Neighborhood, Ann Arbor, Michigan,", 1971 (Box 14)
  - Stout, Mel. "Study Profile-Mackinac Island,", 1971 (Box 14)
  - Thorvaldson, Finn. "Visual Planning-Nixon Rd.," (re: Ann Arbor, Michigan), 1971 (Box 14)
  - Troy, John. "Boardman River Watershed Study,", 1972 (Box 14)
  - Troy, John S. "A Study Framework on the Future Development of Mackinaw Island,", 1971 (Box 14)
  - Verhoeven, James A. "A Survey of Washtenaw County's Recreational System with Policy Implications Derived from the Survey,", 1971 (Box 14)
  - Vickers, Marlys. "Study Profile of Mackinac Island,", 1971 (Box 14)
  - Young, George. "Central Campus Housing Study," (re: University of Michigan), 1965 (Box 14)
- Dean's Topical Files, 1967-1990; 11.5 linear feet
  The Dean's Topical Files, 1967-1990 series consists of the central files maintained in the office of the dean. Activities and functions documented here include those within SNR, communications and cooperative efforts with other university units, and involvement with external organizations. The Topical Files are divided into subseries reflecting the various accession in which materials were received from the school. The subseries, identified by the date range of the materials, are arranged alphabetically. The subject headings frequently continue from one subseries to the next.
  - 1967-1983
    The Dean's Topical Files, 1967-1983 subseries (3 linear ft.) includes material form the tenures of deans Keith Arnold, James T. McFadden, Charles Olsen, and William J. Johnson. Documentation of internal school activities includes affirmative action initiatives ("Affirmative Action," "Minority Recruitment"), faculty governance and development ("Faculty Retreats," "Faculty Bylaws and Code"), and student statistics ("Faculty-Student Ratios," "Graduate Student Attrition," "Undergraduate Enrollment"). SNR's cooperation with other university units is documented under such topics as "Dual Degree with Dearborn," "Continuing Education," and "Center for Research on Learning and Teaching." Two external organizations with whom SNR's involvement is well-documented are the Great Lakes Basin Commission and Great Lakes Tomorrow, Inc.
    - "A" (general correspondence), 1966-1975 (Box 15)
    - Academic Counseling Procedures, 1980 (Box 15)
    - Academic Planning and Analysis, 1977 (Box 15)
    - Administrative Staffing, 1976-1981 (Box 15)
    - Admissions, 1978 (Box 15)
    - Affirmative Action, 1969-1978 (Box 15)
    - Agency for International Development, 1979-1981 (Box 15)
    - Alumni Society
      - Board of Governors, 1976; 1978; 1980 (Box 15)
      - Meetings
        - October 6-7, 1978 (Box 15)
        - January 25, 1979 (Box 15)
        - May 18, 1979 (Box 15)
    - Andrews, Richard N. L., 1980 (Box 15)
    - Ann Arbor Chamber of Commerce, 1977 (Box 15)
    - Arnold, R. Keith, 1965 (Box 15)
    - Associate Vice President for Educational Resources, 1974 (Box 15)
    - Availability Assessments, 1973-1982 (Box 15)
    - "B" (general correspondence), 1967-1980 (Box 15)
    - Barbour-Waterman Demolition, 1976 (Box 15)
    - Bassett, John R. & et al. "User Study: Characteristics and Attitudes Michigan's Au Sable River,", 1972 (Box 15)
    - Breitmeyer, Bruce, Manager of Forest Properties, 1975-1976 (Box 15)
    - "C" (general correspondence), 1977-1979 (Box 15)
    - Carter, Jimmy, 1979 (Box 15)
    - CATIE, 1981 (Box 15)
    - Center for Research on Learning and Teaching, 1976-1978 (Box 15)
    - Center for Strategic Wildlands Management, 1981-1982 (Box 15)
    - College of Architecture and Urban Planning, 1976-1981 (Box 15)
    - Communications Efforts, 1976-1979 (Box 15)
    - Computer Games, 1976-1978 (Box 15)
    - Computer Operations, 1975-1983 (Box 15)
    - Consortium For International Fisheries and Aquaculture Developments, 1979 (Box 15)
    - Continuing Education, 1979-1981 (Box 15)
    - Contractual Research Planning, 1980 (Box 15)
    - Cooperative Education Program, 1981 (Box 15)
    - "D" (general correspondence), 1975-1978 (Box 15)
    - Dana Building Blueprints, undated (Folder 1)
      (call no. Bimu/C241)
    - Dana, Samuel Trask
      - Book Royalties, 1976-1977 (Box 15)
      - Chair of Outdoor Recreation, 1966-1967 (Box 15)
      - General, 1972-1978 (Box 15)
    - Dual Degree with Dearborn, 1981 (Box 15)
    - Duke, Richard D., 1974 (Box 15)
    - "E" (general correspondence), 1968-1979 (Box 15)
    - Eastern Caribbean Natural Area Management Program, 1979 (Box 15)
    - Educational Development Plan, 1977-1978 (Box 15)
    - Ekdahl Lecture Series/KSU, 1981 (Box 15)
    - Energy Economics, 1979 (Box 15)
    - Environmental Education, 1979 (Box 15)
    - Environmental Impact Statement, 1975 (Box 15)
    - Environmental Research Institute of Michigan, 1974 (Box 15)
    - Extension Service, 1977 (Box 15)
    - "F" (general correspondence), 1967-1981 (Box 16)
    - Faculty Bylaws and Code, 1973; 1980 (Box 16)
    - Faculty Contracts, 1977-1978 (Box 16)
    - Faculty Distribution of Effort, 1979 (Box 16)
    - Faculty Retreats
      - 1966 (Box 16)
      - 1967 (Box 16)
      - 1979, 2 folders (Box 16)
      - 1982 (Box 16)
    - Faculty-Student Ratios, 1977 (Box 16)
    - Faculty Work Day, 1983 (Box 16)
    - Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations, 1969-1973 (Box 16)
    - Ford Foundation, 1976-1977 (Box 16)
    - "G" (general correspondence), 1966-1975 (Box 16)
    - Geography (discontinuance), 1981 (Box 16)
    - Gold, Seymour, 1975-1976 (Box 16)
    - Graduate Employees' Organization Strike, 1974-1975 (Box 16)
    - Graduate Student Attrition, 1979 (Box 16)
    - Great Lakes Basin Commission
      - Annual Reports, 1971; 1975; 1977 (Box 16)
      - Correspondence, 1974-1979 (Box 16)
      - Great Lakes Basin Plan, 1977 (Box 16)
      - Priorities Report, 1977 (Box 16)
      - Transportation Memoranda, 1976-1981 (Box 16)
      - Water Resource Policy, 1977 (Box 16)
    - Great Lakes Tomorrow
      - Annual Meeting, 1977-1979 (Box 16)
      - Correspondence, 1976-1978 (Box 16)
      - Executive Committee and Board of Directors Meetings, 1976-1977 (Box 16)
      - Miscellaneous, 1976 (Box 16)
      - Reports and Position Papers, 1976-1977 (Box 16)
    - "H" (general correspondence), 1977-1979 (Box 16)
    - Honorary Degrees, 1970-1971 (Box 16)
    - "I" (general correspondence), 1976-1981 (Box 16)
    - Integrated Impact Assessment, 1979-1980 (Box 16)
    - International Academic Partnerships, 1979 (Box 16)
    - International Seminar on Forest Planning and Management, 1981 (Box 16)
    - International Program Interests, 1975 (Box 16)
    - Internships, Federal Agency, 1977 (Box 16)
    - Johnson, William J., 1963-1976 (Box 16)
    - Kaplan, Rachel, 1973-1977 (Box 16)
    - Memberships, Professional Organizations, 1977 (Box 16)
    - Michigan Society of Fellows, 1973-1977 (Box 16)
    - Michigan State Bar Association Natural Resources and Environmental Law Committee, 1975-1976 (Box 16)
    - Miller, Kenton R., 1971 (Box 16)
    - Minority Affairs Office
      - General, 1972-1978; 2 folders (Box 16)
      - Kilkenny, James, 1973-1978 (Box 51)
    - Minority Recruitment, 1980 (Box 16)
    - National Institute of Health, 1977-1979 (Box 17)
    - News Releases, 1970-1981 (Box 17)
    - North Campus Move, 1970-1971 (Box 17)
    - Office of University Relations and Development, 1968-1975 (Box 17)
    - Open House, 1978 (Box 17)
    - Organization of American States Fellowship Programs, 1975-1979 (Box 17)
    - Outreach, Office of, 1977-1978 (Box 17)
    - "P" (general correspondence), 1976-1981 (Box 17)
    - Peer Information Exchange, 1975-1977 (Box 17)
    - Power Foundation, 1981 (Box 17)
    - President, Office of, 1970-1971 (Box 17)
    - Preston, Stephen B., 1970-1981 (Box 17)
    - Redford, Robert, Project, 1980 (Box 17)
    - Registrar's Office, 1972-1974 (Box 17)
    - Research, 1978-1982 (Box 17)
    - Resources for the Future, Inc., 1971 (Box 17)
    - Rhodes, Frank H. T., 1977 (Box 17)
    - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, 1973-1983 (Box 17)
    - Roth, Filibert, undated (Box 17)
    - School of Natural Resources
      - Description, 1967 (Box 17)
      - Directions, 1972-1975 (Box 17)
      - Evaluations, 1982 (Box 17)
      - Interests in Special Projects, 1975-1976 (Box 17)
      - Recruitment, 1979 (Box 17)
    - Search Position Framework, 1977-1978 (Box 17)
    - Search Protocol, 1981 (Box 17)
    - Shapiro, Harold T., 1977-1979 (Box 17)
    - Society of American Foresters, 1967-1976 (Box 17)
    - Special Events, 1978-1979 (Box 17)
    - Spurr, Stephen Hopkins, 1968 (Box 17)
    - Staebler, George, 1974-1980 (Box 17)
    - Student Alliance for Landscape Architecture, 1977-1978 (Box 17)
    - Student Council, 1967-1968 (Box 17)
    - Tenneco, 1971-1973 (Box 17)
    - Tenure, 1975-1976 (Box 17)
    - Tenure Complaint, 1975 (Box 51)
    - Tinker Foundation, Inc., 1978-1979 (Box 17)
    - Train, Russell E., 1980 (Box 17)
    - Transportation Research Office, 1975 (Box 17)
    - Tuition, 1976-1980 (Box 17)
    - Turner Fund, Scott, 1973-1974 (Box 17)
    - Undergraduate Enrollment, 1983 (Box 17)
    - United States Department of Agriculture
      - Cooperative Research Service, 1972-1975 (Box 17)
      - Extension Service, 1976-1979 (Box 17)
      - Forest Service, 1975-1979 (Box 17)
    - University of Michigan, Flint, 1977 (Box 17)
    - University Planning Seminar, 1969 (Box 17)
    - Urban and Minority Problems Survey, 1967 (Box 17)
    - Visiting Lecturers, 1979 (Box 17)
    - "W" (general correspondence), 1981 (Box 17)
    - Washtenaw County Parks and Recreation Commission, 1974-1982 (Box 17)
    - Washtenaw Land Conservancy, Inc., 1974-1978 (Box 17)
    - Water Related Interests, 1980 (Box 17)
    - Watershed Management, 1980 (Box 17)
    - Weber, Helen A., 1975-1978 (Box 17)
    - Webster, Henry, 1979 (Box 17)
    - Weyerhaeuser, 1976-1978 (Box 17)
    - Wood Energy Project, 1979 (Box 17)
    - World Wildlife Fund, 1978-1980 (Box 17)
    - Xi Sigma Pi, 1976-1978 (Box 17)
  - 1977-1990
    The 1977-1990 subseries of the Dean's Topical Files (8.5 linear ft., received in the 1989-1991 accessions) spans the years 1977 to 1990 and consists of the central files maintained in the office of the dean. It includes files form the tenures of deans William H. Johnson and James Crowfoot. The responsibilities of the dean are broad, ranging from SNR administrative and curricular issues, to communication and cooperative efforts with other university units, to interactions with professional organizations. Also documented here are the school's contributions to professional development ("International Seminars"). Documentation of SNR internal activities in this subseries is strong and can be found under such folder headings as "Administrative Team Retreats," "Courses and Curricula," "Faculty," "Masters Projects," and "Specialization Coordinators." Examples of SNR's cooperation with other university units include "Extension Service," "Continuing Education/ Midcareer Programs," and "Joint Programs and Interunit Initiatives." Both the Wildland Management Center and the Meeman Archive are well-documented.
    - Academic Planning and Analysis, Office of, 1989 (Box 26)
    - Academic Programs, Office of (SNR), Workplan, 1987/88 (Box 26)
    - Administrative Leadership Group (SNR), 1989-1990 (Box 26)
    - Administrative Team Retreats and Meetings, 1986/87-1989/90; 6 folders (Box 26)
    - Affirmative Action, 1982-1990 (Box 26)
    - Alumni, 1986; 1988 (Box 26)
    - Aquatic Research, 1989 (Box 26)
    - Association for Integrated Studies, 1987 (Box 26)
    - Atmospheric Deposition Project, 1985-1990 (Box 26)
    - Banzhaf, William H., correspondence, 1986-1989 (Box 26)
    - Benin, National University of, 1985-1989; 2 folders (Box 26)
    - Botanical Gardens (Matthaei), 1985-1987 (Box 26)
    - Budget, 1984/85-1989/90; 6 folders (Box 26)
    - Bureau of Land Management, 1989-1990 (Box 26)
    - Bylaws, revision of, 1980-1988; 2 folders (Box 27)
    - Camp Filibert Roth (see Field Studies) (Box 27)
    - Career Planning (for students), 1985-1989 (Box 27)
    - Cartography, 1978-1984 (Box 27)
    - CATIE (Centro Agronomico Tropical de Investigacion y Ensenanza), 1984-1986 (Box 27)
    - China, 1983-1986 (Box 27)
    - Collegiate Institute for Values and Science, 1986-1990 (Box 27)
    - Commencements and Honors Convocations, 1985-1990 (Box 27)
    - Committee Assignments and Objectives, 1981-1988 (Box 27)
    - Communications Courses, 1982-1983 (Box 27)
    - Community College Collaboration, 1984-1988 (Box 27)
    - Computers, 1982-1990; 2 folders (Box 27)
    - Concentration Courses, 1986-1987 (Box 27)
    - Conference on Teaching of Ethics and Values (Box 27)
      (see Collegiate Institute for Values and Science)
    - Conservation Biology, Second Conference on, 1985 (Box 27)
      (see also Wildlife Management Center)
    - Consortium for International Fisheries and Aquaculture Development, 1985-1989 (Box 27)
    - Continuing Education/Midcareer Programs, 1983-1985 (Box 27)
    - Cooperative and Joint Activities (with non-UM organizations), 1983-1986 (Box 27)
    - Courses and Curricula
      - General, 1982-1990 (Box 27)
        (includes collaborative efforts with UM units)
      - NR 502: Integrative Problem Solving, 1987-1990; 2 folders (Box 27)
      - NR 570: Microeconomics with Natural Resource Applications, 1989 (Box 27)
      - NR 741: Research Paradigms, 1987-1988 (Box 27)
    - CRLT (Center for Research on Learning and Teaching) Faculty Development Teaching Grants, 1983-1984 (Box 27)
    - Cross-Cultural Training, 1985 (Box 27)
    - Deanship (SNR)
      - General, 1982-1990 (Box 27)
      - Appointments, 1982; 1984 (Box 53)
    - Detroit Area Study, 1989-1990 (Box 27)
    - Division of Research Development and Administration, 1985-1987 (Box 27)
    - Dow Post-Doctoral Research Fellowship, 1987-1988 (Box 27)
    - Earth Day, 1990 (Box 28)